｢先生 こんにちは｡
坂田金時です｡
あんまり
意識しなくて いいから…｡
(銀時)え～ 鳥取県｡
みんな 江戸の人から
とったりしてますが➡
ちょっと ﾊﾟｸっただけなんで➡
はい ずばり お答えしましょう｡
あっ でも 別に 銀さんは➡
ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ ｺｰﾋｰ派さんからの質問｡
つうか その ｲﾒｰｼﾞ映像は なんだ？
それじゃあ まるで
裸ｴﾌﾟﾛﾝじゃねえか！
昔話で有名な
『金太郎』さんですね～｡
ずっと 思ってたのですが
『銀魂』に出てくる ｷｬﾗって➡
銀さんは
誰から 取ってあるんですか？
金太郎の子孫とか
そういう設定では ないんで➡
昔話でも
熊と 相撲を とったりしてます｡
江戸時代の人ではなく
平安時代の人です｡
というわけで
まったく 関係ないけど➡
後に 源 頼光の
四天王の １人となって➡
[A Brief Third Year, Group Z Ginpachi-sensei]
一説では やまんばの子供とされ
怪力無双｡
大江山の 酒呑童子という鬼を
退治したと いわれています｡
A brief...
ﾜﾝﾋﾟｰｽ学園の ｵｵﾆｼ！
ﾜﾝﾋﾟｰｽ学園の廊下に 立ってなさい｡
Ginpachi-sensei!
Umm... This is a question from Coffee Lover in Tottori Prefecture.
"Good day, Sensei. I've been wondering about this for a while.
All the characters in GinTama are based off real people from the Edo Period.
Who is Gin-san based off of?"
Here's your answer. It's Kintoki Sakata.
[Kintoki Sakata]
He's the famous Kintaro-san from folklore.
He's not from the Edo Period, but the Heian Period.
In one story, he's the son of a mountain hag and has peerless strength.
He used to wrestle bears in the folktales.
Afterwards, he became one of Minamoto no Yorimitsu's four guardians.
He is said to have defeated the demon, Shutendoji of Ooe Yama.
But Gin-san isn't a descendant of Kintaro.
He was just modeled a bit after him. Don't be too concerned about it.
That aside, what's with that conceptual art?
I look like I'm wearing an apron in the buff.
Anyway, this is completely unrelated, but Onishi of the One Piece Academy,
stand in the One Piece Academy hall.
[Even though spring is near, there's a mysterious long line in such cold weather this late at night... What could it be?!]
[By the way, there's a bronze statue of a Gundam in front of the Kamiigusa Station.]
["Play Video Games for Only An Hour A Day"]
♪♪～
[The OwEe on sale!! Otaku are lining up!!]
[An undying pop star has her long-awaited first album concert]
[Infiltration!! The other side of Kabukicho]
A Holy Land for otaku, where there are rows of mega stores...
＜大型量販店の建ち並ぶ
ｵﾀｸの聖地 秋葉原！
[Akihabara, the Holy Land]
Akihabara
Tonight, there are many passionate otaku gathering in this Holy Land.
この聖地に 熱きｵﾀｸたちが
今夜 大集結している！＞
(花野ｱﾅ)電機屋の前に並ぶ
長蛇の列｡
[Long lines]
There are long lines in front of the appliance shops.
(花野ｱﾅ)まだ 肌寒い
夜の帳のなか 居並ぶｵﾀｸたち｡
[Saki Hanano - Edo, Akihabara]
It is a chilly night, but these otaku are all standing in line.
彼らの お目当てとは!?
What could they be after?
＜新型ｹﾞｰﾑ機 弁天堂 Owee！
It is the new game console, the Bentendo OwEe!
[Note: Parody of Nintendo Wii.]
この度 とうとう発売される
このｹﾞｰﾑ機を➡
It is about to go on sale. In order to get it before everyone else...
誰よりも早く 手に入れるため➡
熱きｵﾀｸたちの聖戦が
今 始まろうとしている！＞
A holy war is about to begin between passionate otaku!
[A Night of Long Lines... An Otaku Holy War!!]
[OwEe on sale,
an otaku battle]
[How long have you been standing
in line to buy the OwEe?]
I've been here since yesterday evening.
[Yesterday Evening]
(男)でも すでに
並んでる人がいて➡
But there were already people here before me...
上には 上が いるな～｡
There's always someone better than you.
[OwEe on sale,
an otaku battle]
[How long have you
been in line?]
(武蔵)三年前かな～！
I've been here since three years ago.
[For three years]
Huh? My daughter said she wanted one.
[OwEe on sale,
an otaku battle]
[An older man...]
(松平)娘がよ
欲しいっつうから…｡
[For His Daughter]
Hey, you, wanna trade places with me?
よっ ﾃﾒｴ｡ おじさんと 代われ｡
I'm not interested in video games.
[There are even women...]
[OwEe on sale,
an otaku battle]
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)ｹﾞｰﾑなんて
興味ないです｡
ﾈｯﾄｵｰｸｼｮﾝで
高値で 売りさばきま～す｡
I'm going to sell it for a high price on an internet auction.
というように
理由は さまざまですが➡
As you can see, all the people gathered here have many different reasons for being here.
ここに集まった 人々｡
事実確認は できていませんが
Oweeは 先着100名にしか➡
I can't confirm this,
but I have information that the OwEe will only be given to the first hundred people.
行き届かないとの情報も
入っています｡
果たして 彼らは Oweeを
手に入れることが できるのか!?
Will these people be able to get an OwEe? This is all very interesting...
非常に 興味のある…｡
なに？ この煙…｡
(咳込む声)
Where is this smoke coming from?
(店員)あの… お客様…｡
Umm, sirs...
(店員)焚き火とか そういうのは
ご遠慮 願えますか？
Please don't start fires.
他の お客様の ご迷惑…｡
(咳込む声)
It's bothering the other customers...
It's cold. Can't you let us warm up?
寒いんす…｡
暖を とるくらい
勘弁してもらえないかね？
(店員)いや 暖って…➡
Warm up? This is becoming a fire hazard...
もう ちょっとした
ﾎﾞﾔ騒ぎみたいに なってるし…｡
(咳込む声)
And everyone's waiting in line.
(店員)みんな
並んでるわけですから…｡
♪♪～
Wow, that looks delicious.
[Note: Her rosy cheeks are a parody of Heidi from the Heidi anime.]
(神楽)わぁ～ おいしそう！
んっ？ あっ！
All right, it's ready, Kagura.
[Note: He's acting like Grandpa from the Heidi anime.]
よ～し！ 焼けたぞ～ 神楽！
ｱﾊｯ！
いや… 焼けたぞ～ じゃなくて
聞いてますか？ 人の話｡
N-Now's not the time for that. Are you even listening to me?
ほぉ～！ 自分で 気がついたか…｡
Oh? So you noticed.
だが
まだ 足りないものが あるな…｡
There's still something missing.
これは どうしようか？
What should we do with this?
つうか ﾑﾀﾞに うまそう！
That looks extremely delicious!! Heidi?! Is that what Heidi ate?!
ﾊｲｼﾞ!? ﾊｲｼﾞが 食ってたﾔﾂ!?
さぁ 食べなさい｡
Now eat.
What are they doing?!
(男)なんだよ ｱｲﾂら!?
なんで 行列の真ん中で➡
Why are they eating what Heidi ate in the middle of the line?!
ﾊｲｼﾞのﾔﾂ 食ってんだよ～！
(男)なんか 腹立つ！
How annoying!! I'm annoyed, but it looks so good!!
腹立つけど うまそう！
んっ？
(神楽)ﾍﾟｰﾀｰ！
Peter!!
Uhh...umm...
[Note: He's acting like Peter from the Heidi anime.]
(新八)あの… その…｡
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ！
大将 おいしい干し肉も あるから
大将も おあがんなさい｡
General, I have some delicious beef jerky.
Why don't you have some with us?
えぇ～っ!? いいの～!?
What?! Really?
(神楽)ｳﾌﾌ！ ﾍﾟｰﾀｰ こっちよ～！
わ～い！
Peter, over here!
Yeah!
This is bad... My stomach... I've been trying to resist the urge to eat...
(男)いかん… 腹が…｡
食うものも食わず
我慢してきたのに… うぅっ…｡
Grandpa, let's share this with the villagers.
おじいさん 村の人たちにも
分けてあげようよ！
体も温まるし きっと喜ぶわ！
It'll warm them up. I'm sure they'll be pleased.
Oh, Kagura, what a kind girl you are.
おやおや 神楽｡
お前は 優しい子だね～｡
…でも いけないよ～｡
But we cannot.
This is cheese made from the milk of the goats we raised.
これは 私たちが育てたﾔｷﾞから
搾り取った乳で 作られしﾁｰｽﾞ！
働かざる者 食うべからず！
Those who don't work, don't eat. It's sad, but it's the law of the Alps.
かわいそうだが…
これが ｱﾙﾌﾟｽの掟だ！
In order to get something you must give something of equal value.
何かを得るには
それ相応の代償が 必要なんだよ！
例えば そうだね…➡
彼らが並ぶ 順番を
交代してくれるとか｡
For example, trading places in line.
もちろん 前の人 限定だが…｡
Of course, it's limited to those who are in front of us.
うぉ～ 腹立つ～！
腹立つけど 超 うまそ～！
That's so annoying! It's annoying, but it looks so good!
ﾁｷｼｮｰ!! もう 我慢できん!!
Damn it! I can't take it anymore! We'll trade places with you.
ｷﾐたち！ ﾎﾞｸが
代わってあげるから ﾊｲｼﾞを～!!
Give me some Heidi food!
(男)待て！ ﾊｲｼﾞは ｵﾚのものだ！
Wait! That Heidi food is mine!
小さい頃 ﾃﾚﾋﾞで観てから
ずっと 食べたかったんだ～!!
I've been dying to eat that ever since I saw it on TV when I was little!
Oh! Don't disrupt the line!!
(店員)あぁ～！
列を 乱さないでください！
Heidi!!
(男)ﾊｲｼﾞ～!!
Never mind that. It's dangerous!
(店員)ﾊｲｼﾞじゃなくて！
危ないから～!!
That was easy.
(神楽)ちょろいもんよ｡
We've moved twenty places ahead, but we still have a long way to go.
これで
20番くらい前に 進みましたか｡
でも まだまだ 先は遠いですね…｡
ったく… なにが 悲しくて
こんな時間に➡
Jeez. What's more pathetic than having to wait in line for a kid's toy?
ｶﾞｷの おもちゃ買いに
並ばにゃ ならねえんだ…｡
そう思う人が いるから
仕事が 回ってきたわけでしょう？
We got this job because there are people who think like that.
欲しいもんが あるなら
ﾃﾒｴで並んで➡
If you want something, then stand in line yourself.
手に 入れやがれっつうの！
万事屋つったって➡
We may be Odd Jobs but we're not servants. Right?
ﾊﾟｼﾘじゃねえんだよ ﾊﾟｼﾘじゃ～！
えぇ～？
同じ依頼が ５件｡
ｹﾞｰﾑ機が ５台か…｡
We got five identical requests. Five game consoles, huh?
この状況じゃ 手に入れるのは
至難の技ですね…｡
It'll be difficult to get one in this situation.
世も 末だぜ…｡
It's the end of the world when there are this many people who'd line up for a kid's toy...
たかが ｶﾞｷの おもちゃに
並ぶﾔﾂが これほど いようとは…｡
The world is corrupt.
世の中 腐ってやがらあ！
ぶっ壊そうとする ﾂﾞﾗの気持も➡
I'm beginning to understand Zura's feelings about wanting to destroy it.
ちっとは
わかりそうな気が してきたよ｡
Umm, Mr. Samurai, I'm very sorry, but...
(店員)あの お侍様…
申し訳ございません｡
(店員)他の お客様の
ご迷惑に なりますので➡
Your kotatsu is bothering the other customers...
[Note: A kotatsu is a low table with an electric blanket sitting atop it.]
こたつは ちょっと…｡
Sorry. Wait one moment. Elizabeth is still eating.
(桂)すみません｡
ちょっと 待ってください｡
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが まだ 食べてるんで…｡
In that case, leave the line and move over there.
(店員)いや それでしたら あの…
列を離れて 向こうのほうで…｡
(桂)ちょっと 待ってください｡
すぐ…｡
Wait a second. We'll be quick...
いや ちょっと…｡
いや ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
No, just...
No, Elizabeth is...
だから ちょっと…｡
だから ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
I said, just...
I said that Elizabeth is...
No, just...
Elizabeth is still eating!!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが
まだ 食べてるでしょうが～!!
だは～っ!!
やりましたね｡
All right. We moved up ten places.
これで また
10番くらい前に 進みましたよ｡
(神楽)まだまだ 先は 遠いｱﾙな～｡
We've still got a long way to go.
武士とも あろう者が
横入りとは…｡
For a warrior to steal some else's place in line... Gintoki, you've become a real jerk.
銀時 ｷｻﾏも 落ちたな｡
うるさいよ！ 光の速さで
地上に 落下してるﾔﾂに➡
Shut up.
I don't need to be told that by someone who crashed into the ground at light speed.
言われたかねえよ！
I've been in line since 4:00 A.M. yesterday.
こっちは
昨日の 朝４時から 並んでるんだ｡
ｼﾞｬﾏするとあらば
お前でも斬るぞ 銀時！
If you interfere, I'll kill even you, Gintoki.
革命家が 流行に乗って
ｹﾞｰﾑ買いに並びに来たんですか？
What's a revolutionary doing getting caught up in a fad and coming here to buy a game console?
(桂)世の中の流れが
どこに向かっているのか➡
We need to know which way the world is headed.
ｵﾚたちは 知る必要がある｡
たとえ ﾌｧﾐｺﾝのことでもだ｡
Even if it's just for a Famicom.
[Note: Famicom is what the Nintendo (NES) is called in Asia.]
That's old!
古いよ！
ｹﾞｰﾑを ﾌｧﾐｺﾝって呼んでる時点で➡
You're not keeping up with the times when you call a game console a Famicom!!
流れに ついていけてねえよ！
なんでも
今度のﾌｧﾐｺﾝは すごいらしいな｡
It seems that this Famicom is amazing.
ﾌｧﾐｺﾝと ﾃﾞｨｽｸｼｽﾃﾑが一体化した
ﾂｲﾝﾌｧﾐｺﾝとかいう…｡
It's a combination of a Famicom and a Disk System, a Twin Famicom...
[Note: The Twin Famicom console was released only in Japan.]
お前 ﾎﾝﾄに ﾌｧﾐｺﾝ
買いに来たんかい～！
Did you actually come here to buy a Famicom?!
なんのために
並んでんだ ｵﾒｴは！
Why are you in line?!
そういう列じゃねえよ この列は！
That's not what this line is for!!
つうか ねえよ そんな列！
売ってねえよ そんなもん もう！
Anyway, that line doesn't exist!! They don't sell those anymore!
What? I thought I could see Mario once more. You saying I can't?
(桂)なんだと？
ﾏﾘｵと 再び 会えると思ったのに➡
その道は 閉ざされたか！
再びどころか 何十回も
よみがえってるよ あの ｵｯｻﾝ！
Once more? That man has been revived dozens of times!!
[Note: Mario has appeared in dozens of new series since 1983.]
(桂)そうか… あのｺﾝﾌﾟﾚｯｸｽの塊の
弟のほうも 健在なのか？
I see... Is his younger brother with the inferiority complex still thriving?
いやなこと言うんじゃねえよ！
お前に ﾙｲｰｼﾞの何がわかるんだよ！
What a terrible thing to say! What do you know about Luigi?!
だいたい お前… 変装もせずに
こんなとこに ﾉｺﾉｺ来やがって！
Anyway, how can you come here without a disguise?
指名手配犯だっつうのを
忘れたか？
Did you forget that you're a wanted criminal?
ﾌﾝ… こんな時間に
こんなところにいる➡
No police officers would have the time to come to a place like this at this hour.
暇な警察など おるまい｡
暇な革命家は いるんですね｡
I guess some revolutionaries have a lot of free time.
(店員)
申しわけありません お客様｡
I'm very sorry, sirs...
他のお客様の
ご迷惑になりますので➡
Your bath is bothering the other customers...
お風呂は ちょっと…｡
(沖田)なんだ こら…
こっちは 徹夜で並んでんだ｡
What of it? We've been in line all night.
風呂くらい入りたいだろ？
(近藤)やめろ 総悟！
We should at least be able to take a bath.
Stop, Sogo. Sorry, I'll be finished soon.
すみません すぐ終わりますんで｡
まだ あそこ 洗ってないんで…｡
I still haven't washed myself down there, yet...
(店員)いや もう警察呼びますよ！
No, I'm going to call the police.
(近藤)いや ﾎﾞｸら 警察なんで…｡
No, we are the police.
だから 警察呼び…｡
だから ﾎﾞｸら…｡
I said, I'm calling the police...
I said, we're...
No, just...
いや ちょっ…｡
いや ちょっ…！
No, just...
Umm, just...
J-Just...
ちょっ！ まだ あそこ
洗ってないでしょうがぁぁ～!!
Just a moment! I still haven't washed myself down there yet!!
(２人)うぐっ!!
だから どこの国から？
Just how rude can some people get?
とりあえず
この国は もう終わりっすよ｡
Some people will try anything to cut in line.
ﾁｯ… 真選組の連中と
こんなところで出くわすとは…｡
Tsk... I never expected to run into the Shinsengumi here.
ﾊﾞｶたちによる
奇跡的な競演ですよ｡
An unbelievable performance by a bunch of idiots.
あっ こっちに気づいた！
Oh, they noticed us!!
(神楽)
ﾂﾞﾗ 早く ｺﾀﾂの中に隠れるね！
Zura, hide in the kotatsu immediately.
(桂)ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ｡
I'm not Zura, I'm Katsura.
What are you doing here?
(土方)ﾃﾒｴら
こんなところで 何してやがる？
その台詞 そのまま
ﾊﾞｯﾄで打ち返してやるよ｡
I'm batting that question right back at you.
その台詞を さらに
ﾊﾞｯﾄで打ち返してやるよ｡
I'm batting that question right back at you.
その台詞を…！
もういいです しつこいです｡
I'm batting that...
Enough. It's getting annoying.
(近藤)う～ さむさむさむ！
Ugh... Cold, cold, cold, cold, cold...
あっ ｺﾀﾂだ！
ちょっと 入れてくんない！
Oh, a kotatsu.
Let us in for a second!
あっ 勝手に入るなよ！
Hey! Don't come in without permission!!
(沖田)ｹﾁｹﾁすんじゃねえや！
減るもんじゃあるめえし｡
Don't be so stingy!! It's not a big deal!!
あっ 何々？
お前らも ひょっとして➡
Oh, what's this? Did you come to buy a game console, too?
ｹﾞｰﾑ買いにきたわけ？
ﾌﾟﾌﾟｰｯ 暇なﾔﾂら！
You sure have a lot of free time.
近藤さん… その台詞は➡
Kondo-san, that applies to us, too. Please stop.
すべて ｵﾚたちにも
ふりかかってくるんで➡
やめてくだせぇ｡
(近藤)でも 残念でした～！
Unfortunately, this shop only has a hundred game consoles in stock.
この店の ｹﾞｰﾑの在庫は
100台だけらしい｡
そうさなぁ 列でいうと
ちょうど ﾄｼがいるあたりまでで➡
That's right. They'll run out at just about the place where Toshi is standing in line.
在庫が切れるだろう｡ 残念ながら
お前たちのところまで➡
Unfortunately, you won't get a game console.
ｹﾞｰﾑは 行き届きましぇ～ん！
ﾅﾊﾊﾊ～ 悪いなぁ！
Too bad.
こっちは 昨日の朝から
ここに並んでるんだ｡
We've been in line since yesterday morning. Right, Toshi?
なぁ ﾄｼ！
ｽｩ～…｡
あれ？
なんで ここにいるんだ？ ﾄｼ｡
Huh? Why are you here, Toshi?
(土方)寒いから｡
寒いからじゃねえよっ!!
It's cold.
Don't say that!! Why aren't you holding our place in line?!
なんで 順番
確保してくれねえんだよ！
おい～！ 昨日から並んでたのが
ﾊﾟｰだろうがぁ～!!
Hey! Now all our standing in line since yesterday has gone to waste!!
どうするんだぁ～ ｵﾗｧ～！
What are we going to do?! I made a promise to Otae-san!!
店で お妙さんと
約束しちまったってのによ～！
Get an OwEe for all the hostess club hostesses. If you don't, I'll flick your eyeballs.
((お妙:ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢 全員分の Owee
手に入れてこいや｡
できなかったら 眼球にﾃﾞｺﾋﾟﾝな))
それ 約束じゃねえよ 恐喝だよ！
That's not a promise!! That's a threat!!
(土方)近藤さん 心配いらねえ｡
Kondo-san, don't worry. Yamazaki is holding my place in line.
ｵﾚの代わりに
山崎が並んでるはず｡
土方さん… 山崎なら
あそこで ｶﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ やってますぜ｡
Hijikata-san, Yamazaki is...
Over there playing Kabaddi.
(山崎)ｶﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ ｶﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ ｶﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ…！
Kabaddi, kabaddi, kabaddi, kabaddi...
[Note: Kabaddi is a popular sport in South Asia.]
(土方)山崎～！
誰だ ｿｲﾂらぁ～!!
Yamazaki!! Who are these people?!
12時になりました！
弁天堂 Owee…➡
It's now midnight! The Bentendo OwEe is now on sale!
販売開始いたします！
並んだ順に 慌てず駆けず➡
Stay in line. Don't panic or run.
係員の指示に従い お一人様
１個だけお買い上げと… わっ!?
Follow the employees' directions. One per person...
(２人)うおお～!!
人の話 聞いてるんですか！
(近藤)関係あるか！
Are you listening to me?!
It doesn't matter!! This world is all about survival of the fittest!
世の中… 弱肉強食なんだよ！
All right! I got an OwEe!
よっしゃ～ Owee ｹﾞｯﾄ…｡
うぅえぇぇぇ～!!
ﾃﾒｴに Oweeは 渡さねえ｡
I won't let you have it.
この野郎…｡
You bastard...
Oweeは ｵﾚが 手に入れる～!!
I'm going to get the OwEe!!
させるか～!!
I'm not letting you!!
Oweeは ｵﾚが手に入れる！
I'm going to...
Get the OwEe!!
I've got it!!
もらった！
うらぁぁ～!!
I won't let you have it!!
ﾃﾒｴには 渡さねえ～!!
Oweeは ｵﾚのもんだぁ～!!
The OwEe is mine!
(人々)わぁ～!!
Whoa... Six people charged into the store and customers are following them.
(花野ｱﾅ)あ～っと！
先に飛び込んだ６人につられ➡
客が 次々と
店に飛び込んでいく！
これは 危険… これは 危険です！
This is dangerous. This is really dangerous.
暴動… ほとんど
暴動の体をなしてきました！
A riot!! They've become a rioting mob!!
If something is not done right away, something terrible will happen.
これは 早々に手を打たねば
大変なことになりそうです｡
Owee販売中止にもなりかねない！
The OwEe might be pulled from the sale!!
弁天堂 広報部の山田さんに
お話を伺いたいと思います｡
I'm going to talk to Yamada-san of the Bentendo public relations department.
どうですか？ こういう事態は？
What do you think? Did you expect that this would happen?
山田さんは
予想されていましたか？
Well, pretty much...
(山田)まぁ 大方ね｡
The OwEe release date was delayed several times.
Oweeは 何度も
発売 延期してましたから➡
皆さん 我慢の限界が
きてたんでしょうね｡
Everyone probably couldn't wait any longer.
ｹｶﾞ人が出れば Owee
販売中止も考えられますが｡
Do you think the OwEe will be pulled from the sale if someone gets hurt?
大丈夫です｡
手は 考えてあります｡
It'll be all right. We have a plan.
(山田)平和的で 絶好の
ﾃﾞﾓﾝｽﾄﾚｰｼｮﾝになる解決法を｡
It will be solved peacefully...
And it's a great way to demonstrate how it works.
Wha?! What is that?!
何だ？ あれは！
巨大なﾃﾚﾋﾞ画面と➡
It's a giant TV screen.
Oweeが！
And an OwEe!!
(どよめき)
(店長)ﾜｰﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ！
Do you all want this game console that badly?!
お前ら！
ｹﾞｰﾑが そんなに欲しいか～！
Then win it by playing a game!! Get what you want by playing a game!
(店長)だったら ｹﾞｰﾑで勝ち取れ！
欲しいものは ｹﾞｰﾑで手に入れろ！
それが 真の ｹﾞｰﾏｰというものだ!!
That's what a true gamer would do!!
♪♪～
(店長)ﾄﾞﾜｰﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ！
Do you all want...
お前ら～
ｹﾞｰﾑが そんなに欲しいか～!!
...this game console that badly?!
だったら ｹﾞｰﾑで勝ち取れ！
欲しいものは ｹﾞｰﾑで手に入れろ！
Then win it by playing a game!! Get what you want by playing a game!
それが 真の ｹﾞｰﾏｰというものだ！
That's what a true gamer would do!!
誰ですか？ あれは…｡
店長です｡
Who is that?
The manager.
ｷﾐたち Oweeを
手に入れるために➡
How about participating in a little challenge to win the OwEe?
ちょっとした 賭けに
挑戦してみないか？
ここにいる 選ばれたｹﾞｰﾏｰたち｡
You chosen gamers here...
先ほど 真っ先に飛び込んできた
血気盛んなｹﾞｰﾏｰたち｡
You energetic gamers who rushed in first...
今から 彼らに
２ﾁｰﾑに分かれてもらい➡
I'm going to split you up into two teams and you have to play games against each other.
ｹﾞｰﾑ勝負をやってもらう｡
Hey, what is he saying?
おい 何勝手なこと ぬかしてんだ｡
(店長)もちろん 勝ったﾁｰﾑには
Oweeを ただで差しあげる｡
Naturally, I'll give the winning team OwEes for free.
えっ！
ﾏｼﾞっすか？
Really?!
You are chosen individuals. It's only natural.
(店長)ｷﾐたちは
選ばれた者たちなんだ｡
当然のことさ｡
I want the remaining spectators to predict which team is going to win...
(店長)そして
残った観客の諸君には➡
どちらのﾁｰﾑが勝つか
予想してもらい➡
勝利ﾁｰﾑにﾍﾞｯﾄした者たちに➡
Those who bet on the winning team...
ﾌｯ… このOweeを
購入する権利を与える！
...will get the right to buy the OwEe.
在庫が足らなくても 必ず何とか
目の前に Oweeを用意しよう｡
We'll be sure to get you an OwEe even if we don't have enough in stock.
どうだね？ おもしろい…｡
What do you think? Sounds like fun, right?
(男)おもしろくねえんだよ！
こっちは お前 確実に➡
That doesn't sound like fun!
I was standing in a spot in line where I would've been guaranteed an OwEe!!
Oweeが手に入るくらいの位置に
並んでたんだぞ！
どうしてくれんだよ！
(男)ｵﾒｴ 店長だろ!!
What are you going to do about that?!
You're the manager!!
(男)いい歳こいて
恥ずかしくねえのかよ！
Aren't you embarrassed to be dressed up like that at your age?!
ﾀﾞｧ～ こら ｸｿｶﾞｷどもが！
You damn kids!!
ｹﾞｰﾑばっかりしやがって！
働け ﾊﾞｶ野郎!!
All you do is play video games...
Work, you idiots!! Stop playing video games, stupid!! Die!!
(店長)ｹﾞｰﾑ やめろ！ ﾊﾞｶ!! 死ね！
店長 素に戻ってますね｡
The manager has become himself again.
元も子もないことを言っています｡
He's saying things that won't benefit him.
おい ｶﾞｷども！
Hey, kids.
Do you want that game console that badly?
そんなにｹﾞｰﾑが欲しいか？
だったら ｵﾚたちに賭けな！
Then bet on us.
We'll win the OwEe. 100% guaranteed.
100ﾊﾟｰｾﾝﾄ OWee が手に入るぜ！
(男)ただ者じゃねえ！
高橋名人顔だ!!
They're not normal people!
They look like Master Takahashi! All their chins are turned up!!
[Note: Takahashi Meijin is a famous video game player from the 80s.]
(男)全員
もれなく しゃくれてるぞ！
(近藤)おいおい いいのか？
そんなに簡単に決めちゃって｡
Hey, is it all right to be making your decision so soon?
痛い目 見ることになるぜ！
You'll just get hurt...
Whoa!! Their chins are turned up, too! But the second guy looks embarrassed!
(男)おぉ あっちのほうが
しゃくれてるぞ！
(男)でも ２番目のﾔﾂ 照れてるぞ
ｱｲﾂ ﾀﾞﾒだ!!
He's no good!
What are you saying, you idiot?!
[Note: Hijikata is imitating Antonio Inoki, a famous professional wrestler in Japan. Inoki is also known for his turned up chin.]
なんだ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
(男)ﾀﾞﾒだ ｱｲﾂ…｡
He's no good! He's got it all wrong. He's someone else!
(男)っていうか間違えてるもん
違う人になってるもん！
Damn it!!
(土方)黙れ ﾊｹﾞ！ ｹﾞｰﾑやめろ!!
ﾊﾞｶ 死ね！ お前だけ死ね!!
What did you say?! Damn kids, give up video games! Die, stupid! Just die!
(男)お前が死ね！
You die.
Hey! This has completely turned into a match of the upturned chins!
(男)おい 完全に
ただのしゃくれ対決になってるぞ｡
(笑い声)
This looks kind of interesting. I'll place a bet!!
(男)なんか おもしろそう！
ｵﾚ 賭けよう!!
Me, too!!
ｵﾚも！
拙者も!!
ｱﾁｷも！
Me, too!
(花野ｱﾅ)おぉ
彼らの濃いｷｬﾗに押されて➡
Wow! Impressed by their unique personalities, the customers are placing bets.
お客さんが
次々にﾍﾞｯﾄしていきます｡
ん～ これは 絶好の宣伝ですね｡
Hmm... This is a great advertising scheme.
ｹﾞｰﾑの紹介にもなるし｡
It introduces the game console.
なるほど これを
狙っていたわけですね 山田さん｡
I see. So this is what you were going for, Yamada-san.
それじゃあ まず第１戦目は➡
The first battle is...
ｷﾞｬﾙｹﾞｰ対決！
A girl game battle.
(店長)『ﾊﾞｷﾎﾞｷﾒﾓﾘｱﾙ』!!
このｹﾞｰﾑの主人公になって➡
Bakiboki Memorial!
[Note: Parody of Tokimeki Memorial, a popular dating simulation game.]
You play the main character.
ﾋﾛｲﾝの女の子を先に
おとしたほうの勝利とします！
The person who bonks the heroine first...
...is the winner!
((ﾏｸﾞ子:ｳﾌﾌﾌ…))
[Bakioki Memorial]
ｷﾞｬﾙｹﾞｰ？
んなもん やったことねえぞ！
A girl game? I've never played one of those.
What does he mean by "bonk the heroine"?
ﾋﾛｲﾝをおとすって何？
伝説の崖的なものから？
Does it have something to do with a legendary cliff?
[Note: Parody of the Legendary Tree from Tokimeki Memorial game.
At the end of the game, one girl shows up at the tree to confess her love.]
違いますよ…
女の子と仲よくなって➡
No it doesn't. The point of the game is to become romantic with a girl.
ﾗﾌﾞﾗﾌﾞになるのが目的のｹﾞｰﾑです｡
まずいな… ﾎﾞｸにいたっては➡
This is bad. I haven't played many of these games.
ｹﾞｰﾑ自体
あんまりやったことないよ｡
(近藤)ﾌﾌﾌﾌ… 勝負あったな！
This match is decided.
古今東西
あらゆるｷﾞｬﾙｹﾞｰをやりつくし➡
I've played every girl game ever created and I've bonked countless women.
おとした女は数知れず！
三次元より二次元に
生まれてくればよかったのにと➡
Otae-san even said that I should have been born in 2D instead of 3D.
お妙さんにも称された
この近藤 勲にかかれば➡
For me, Isao Kondo,
ﾋﾛｲﾝの１人や２人
15分あれば十分｡
fifteen minutes is enough for me to take on one or two heroines.
(沖田)いや それ
褒められてませんよ｡
She's not praising you.
She's telling you to die.
死の宣告ですよ｡
(近藤)あらゆるｷﾞｬﾙｹﾞｰを
やりつくしたｵﾚには➡
I've played countless girl games.
新しいｹﾞｰﾑでさえ
どの選択肢を選べば➡
I can tell which choices the girls will like
女の子の好感度が上がるか➡
ﾃﾞｰﾄには どこが最適か
なんとなく読めてしまう｡
and what the best date spots are even in the new games.
If only you could do that in real life.
(沖田)三次元でも活かせればね｡
ｵﾚのｺﾝﾄﾛｰﾗｰさばきには
一分のﾑﾀﾞもないぞ｡
My skill at using a controller doesn't waste a minute.
お前たちについてこれるかな？
Do you think you can keep up?
(桂)ﾌﾌﾌﾌ…｡
誰だ！
(笑い声)
Who's that?!
(桂)一分のﾑﾀﾞもないとは笑わせる｡
You don't waste a minute?
恋愛それそのものが ﾑﾀﾞから
できていることを知らんか！
How silly. Don't you know that love itself is all about excess?
(桂)ﾑﾀﾞに胸をざわめかせ
ﾑﾀﾞに不安になり➡
You get excessively excited, and excessively uneasy.
ﾑﾀﾞにあがき ﾑﾀﾞに終わっていく｡
You struggle excessively. And it all ends in vain.
だが それがﾑﾀﾞなことだったと
誰が言えようか！
Nobody will say that it's a waste. No, love is all about excess!!
いや そのﾑﾀﾞにこそ
人生のすべては詰まっている！
♪♪～
Wh-Who are you?!
な… 何者だ！
(桂)ﾌﾝ ただのしがない配管工さ｡
I'm just an ordinary plumber.
(花野ｱﾅ)
おぉっと！ 突然 現れた➡
Whoa!! A man who calls himself a plumber has suddenly barged into this challenge!
配管工を名乗る男が
ｹﾞｰﾑ勝負に乱入！
いったい何者なんだ!? この男は！
Who is this man?!
なんだ？ ｱｲﾂ！
おい あのｷﾉｺ…｡
Who is he?!
Hey! That mushroom... Could he be the world's most famous plumber, Mari...
あれ ひょっとして 世界で
いちばん有名な配管工 ﾏﾘ…｡
ﾏﾘｵじゃない…｡
I'm not Mario. I'm Katsu-
ｶﾂｵ…｡
うおぉ～！
(桂)あっ やばい ﾋｹﾞが… ﾋｹﾞ｡
This is bad! My mustache... my mustache...
何やってんですか！ 桂さん｡
What are you doing, Katsura-san?!
こんなところに出てきて わざわざ
とっ捕まりにきたんですか！
Did you come out just to get caught?!
ﾂｲﾝﾌｧﾐｺﾝが
ﾀﾀﾞで手に入ると聞いたんでな｡
I heard that I could win a free Twin Famicom.
だから そんなもん
もうないって言ってんでしょ！
They don't have those anymore!
っつうか ｱﾝﾀ
どんだけﾂｲﾝﾌｧﾐｺﾝ 欲しいの？
Anyway, how badly do you want a Twin Famicom?!
そんな うすっぺらな変装じゃ
すぐﾊﾞﾚちゃいますよ！
They'll see through your flimsy disguise in no time!
早く この場から…｡
(土方)おい！
Get away from here quickly.
Hey!
そこの！
《やばい!!
You there.
This is bad! We can't fool the Demon Vice-Chief's eyes!
やっぱり鬼の副長の目は
ごまかせない！》
こんな所で お目にかかれるとは
奇遇じゃねえか！
I never expected to see you here.
What a coincidence. You're done for.
ここで 会ったが百年目｡
あの… あとでｻｲﾝとか
もらっていいすか？ ﾏﾘｵって｡
Umm... Also, could I get your autograph?
I want you to write, "From Mario. To Toshiro-kun," right here...
十四郎君へって
書いてほしいんですが… ここに｡
《奇跡だ！ 奇跡のﾊﾞｶがここに!!》
It's a miracle!! There are miraculous idiots here!!
いや ｻｲﾝはちょっと…｡
Well, I don't really do signatures...
１人書くとﾌﾞﾜｰと来て
きりがなくなっちゃうんで｡
When I do one, a bunch of people tend to gather and there's no end to it.
そうすか…
じゃあ 写メ いいっすか？
I see. Then how about a photo? I won't show it to anyone.
誰にも見せないんで…｡
じゃあ握手だけでも…｡
Then how about a handshake? I'm a real Bentendo fan.
根っからの弁天堂派なんです ｵﾚ｡
How clingy is he going to get?! No such creepy Mario exists.
《っつうか どんだけ
食いついてんだよ この人｡
こんな気持の悪いﾏﾘｵ いねえよ》
土方さん ちょいと待ちなせえ！
Hijikata-san, wait just a second.
騙されちゃいけやせんよ｡
You mustn't be fooled.
《やばい 沖田さん！
この人は鼻がきくから…》
Oh no, it's Okita-san! He's very perceptive.
(沖田)そんな長髪のﾏﾘｵなんざ
見たことねえぜ！
I've never seen a Mario with such long hair.
ｵﾚは騙されねえよ…
ｿｲﾂは偽者だ！
I can't just stand by quietly... He's a fake.
本物は… あっちだ！
The real one's over there.
[Give it your best, Katsuo.]
《あんなﾏﾘｵも見たことあるかぁ！
I've never seen a Mario like that, either!!
お前ら ﾋｹﾞがあったら
何でもﾏﾘｵかぁ！》
You two think that anything with a mustache is Mario, don't you?!
(土方)ﾊﾞｶか？ ｵﾒｴは…｡
What are you, stupid?
That's got to be his younger brother, Luigi. He's green.
あれは 弟さんのﾙｲｰｼﾞさんに
決まってんだろう 緑色だろうが｡
ｾﾞｶﾞ派は黙って ﾄﾞﾘｷｬｽやってろ ﾎﾞｹ｡
You Zega fans should be quiet and play your Creamcast, stupid.
[Note: Parody of Sega Dreamcast.]
ｼｪﾝﾏｰの続編 ずっと待ってろ ﾎﾞｹ！
Keep waiting for your sequel to Shenmue, stupid.
[Note: Shenmue is a SEGA Dreamcast adventure game. The series has been on hiatus since 2001.]
(沖田)言われなくても
待ち続けまさぁ…｡
I'll keep on waiting no matter what anyone says. I'm sure it'll come back.
きっと いつか帰ってきまさぁ｡
(近藤)やめろ ２人とも！
こんなところで…｡
Both of you stop fighting.
(土方)ｿﾞﾆｰ派は黙ってろや！
Keep quiet you Zony lover.
[Note: Parody of Sony.]
(神楽)すっかり騙されてるｱﾙ｡
They're completely fooled.
Gintoki...
(桂)銀時 ここは ｵﾚに任せろ｡
Leave this to me.
ｵﾚが 危険を冒してまできたのは➡
I didn't risk coming just because I wanted a Twin Famicom.
何もﾂｲﾝﾌｧﾐｺﾝが
欲しかっただけではないぞ｡
Of course. There aren't any Twin Famicoms.
あたりめえだろ！
ﾂｲﾝﾌｧﾐｺﾝなんてねえんだよ!!
(桂)今まで 我々 攘夷志士を
さんざん苦しめてきた真選組｡
The Shinsengumi have been making us Anti-Foreigner Faction members suffer until now.
ｹﾞｰﾑとはいえ
連中をたたきつぶす いい機会だ｡
This is a good chance to crush them, even if it's just at a game.
ﾂﾞﾗ… しくじるなよ｡
Zura, don't screw up. It's over if they find out who you are.
ﾊﾞﾚたら しめえだぞ！
ﾌﾝ…｡
《桂:ﾂﾞﾗじゃない》
I'm not Zura...
ｶﾂｵだ！
I'm Katsuo.
(店長)それでは１戦目
ｷﾞｬﾙｹﾞｰ勝負 はじめ～！
The first battle, the girl game challenge, will now begin!
(歓声)
[Preview]
Now then, everyone, what kind of show will these chosen individuals
give us in order to win the new Bentendo OwEe game console?
The first battle, the girl game challenge, will now begin!
["Life and Video Games are Full of Bugs"]
[Who will win the OwEe? Will it be the Odd Jobs team or the Shinsengumi team?!]
[One more episode of season 2 of the GinTama anime!! Let's keep this up until the end!!]